

Software Developer

👂 Ishwar Nagar, 480661 Seoni, India 🛛 arpansahu@zohomail.in 📞 7828007426 🤘 arpansahu.me

🛗 01/08/1998 🛮 in arpansahu 🌎 arpansahu 🕒 arpanrocks95 💆 arpansahu_

Profile

A Python Full Stack Developer, I've diligently worked on acquiring skills to be a very versatile engineer. have a passion to solve complex real-life problems, quick at wrapping my head around new things.

I love to be in the technological field of work, as technology excites me a lot and I am passionate about it. Today, nothing changes faster than this in the tech world, and rather than trying to keep up with the change I want to be a part of the change and lead the change.

Skills

C, C++, Python, Django, Flask, Fast API, React, Redux, Git, Gitlab, Amazon Web Services, Heroku, Selenium, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Nginx, Postgres, MySql, Sqlite, MongoDB, Redis, Jquery, Linux, Celery, RabbitMQ

Professional Experience

Associate Software Engineer, *Trellix/Fireeye* □

07/2022 - present | Pune, India

- Building SAAS platform for XDR.
- Working on various security marketplace Integrations.
- Build end-to-end Integration between Security Orchestrator and Tenable.
- Build end-to-end Migration processes for customers from EC2 legacy to XDR ecosystem.
- Building a universal Search across different products in Trellix Ecosystem.

Solution Engineer, *Gammastack* ☑

02/2021 - present | Indore, India

- Delivered quality code by applying the best development practices.
- Executed projects and delivered solutions to the clients depending on their business requirements and expectations.
- Liaised and coordinated with stakeholders during problem diagnoses, requirement gathering, detailed level design, development, system test, and production implementation to ensure that optimal resolutions were achieved.
- Built a new type of betting system on betting portal Betfaro, based on Double Bet; the project got a boost, client profits increased up to 60%, and website traffic raised above 40%.
- Contributed to KodeKloud, worked on a few features with MongoDB, Flask, AngularJS
- Built a service to Scrap 12 months of data regarding Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration(USA) and stored it in MySql Database.

Education

Bachelors of Technology (Computer Science),

Lakshmi Narain College of Technology & Excellence ☑

CGPA: 8.55

Higher Secondary, *Shir Ram Adarsh Higher Secondary*

Percentage: 70.40

High Secondary, Bhonsala Military School ☑

Percentage: 88.60

08/2017 – 07/2021 | Bhopal, India

06/2015 – 06/2016 | Seoni, India

05/2013 – 05/2014 | Nagpur, India

Certificates

NPTEL Introduction to Programming with C ☑

- NPTEL Problem Solving through C ☑
- NPTEL Data Structures with Python ☑

- NPTEL Programming with Python ☑
- NPTEL Programming in C++ ☑

Awards

National Aerospace Olympiad, DRDO, Banglore

2013

Interests

Travel, Gaming, Cooking

Languages

English

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$

Hindi



Projects

Technorigger, *Perfect Job & Upgrade Skill Portal* ☑ Checkout Admin Panel **Live** ☑ , Cron Instance **Live** ☑

01/2022 - present

Technologies Used: PYTHON | DJANGO | JQUERY | HTML | CSS | BOOTSTRAP | JAVASCRIPT | POSTGRES | AMAZON | WEB SERVICES | NGINX | OPENSSL | SELENIUM | EC2 | ROUTES3 | WINDSCRIBE VPN | NEO4J | FAST API | GITLAB | DOCKER

Technorigger is built to overcome the drawbacks of Linkedin, Glassdoor, AmbitionBox and Fishbowl. These
companies are In the market for a long time but if we could get all the features of these 4 portals then it would
be heaven for job Seekers and Hiring Companies as well. Build a Django Admin Panel for Admin Panel, Cron
Instance for Scraping and Other utilities in Django, React Front End in Development and also Fast API API
instance in Development

Clock Works, Django Notes & Reminder App ♂

05/2022 - 05/2022

Checkout **Github** or **Live**

Technologies Used: PYTHON | DJANGO | HTML | CSS | BOOTSTRAP | JAVASCRIPT | REDIS | SQLITE | POSTGRES | DJANGO | CHANNELS | MAIL JET | WEB SOCKETS | CELERY | RABBITMQ | HEROKU | GITHUB

Django based Notes Email and Reminder App, Progress bar, where user can see how much task is remaining.
 When Scheduled Reminders are successful, Users are notified and Admin can Schedule Broadcast Notifications for all Users.

arpansahu.me, Django Personal Porfolio 🛭

04/2022 - 05/2022

$\label{technologies} \textbf{Used: PYTHON} \ | \ \textbf{DJANGO} \ | \ \textbf{JQUERY} \ | \ \textbf{HTML} \ | \ \textbf{CSS} \ | \ \textbf{BOOTSTRAP} \ | \ \textbf{JAVASCRIPT} \ | \ \textbf{AMAZON WEBSERVICES} \ | \ \textbf{MAIL JET} \ | \ \textbf{HEROKU} \ | \ \textbf{GITHUB}$

• A simple Django Web App built with bootstrap without any Database as a Portfolio Website, Static files are hosted on AWS S3 Bucket and itself it is hosted on Heroku.

Altered Datum, React Blog App □

04/2021 - 05/2021

Checkout **Github** ☑ or **Live** ☑

Technologies Used: JAVASCRIPT | REACT | REDUX | CSS3 | MATERIAL UI | REACT ROUTER | HEROKU | GITHUB

• Built using Material UI and Implemented Complete User Auth. Admin Panel for management of Blogs available to admins. For normal users, the admin panel is hidden and only blogs and screens related to it are available. Integrated with REST API using Axios at the endpoint 🗷 .

Altered Datum API, Django Rest API App for React Blog App ☑

04/2021 - 05/2021

Checkout **Github** ☑ or **Live** ☑

Technologies Used: PYTHON | DJANGO | DJANGO | REST FRAMEWORK | HTML5 | CSS3 | BOOTSTRAP | JAVASCRIPT | JQUERY | HEROKU | AWS | GITHUB

• Implemented Complete Auth Using Django Custom Auth Model. Integrated Social Login using drf-social-oauth2, which combines normal auth and social auth. Crud Operations with Django Rest Framework for restaurant menu. Schema and Swagger with CORE API are also integrated. Deployed on Heroku. Front end available at ☑

OWL EYES, *Django All Auth Implementation* □

04/2021 - 04/2021

Checkout Github or Live

$\textbf{Technologies Used: PYTHON} \ | \ \textbf{DJANGO} \ | \ \textbf{HTML5} \ | \ \textbf{CSS3} \ | \ \textbf{BOOTSTRAP} \ | \ \textbf{JAVASCRIPT} \ | \ \textbf{POSTGRES} \ | \ \textbf{HEROKU} \ | \ \textbf{GITHUB}$

• Implemented Complete Auth Using **Django All Auth.** Users can log in with a username/email/social account. Custom templates for a lot of functionalities. Integrated GitHub, Google Social Login. Deployed on Heroku.

Geek Glasses, 03/2021 – 03/2021

Django Custom Auth User Model from AbstractBaseUser ☑

Checkout **Github** ♂ or **Live** ♂

$\textbf{Technologies Used: PYTHON} \ | \ \textbf{DJANGO} \ | \ \textbf{HTML5} \ | \ \textbf{CSS3} \ | \ \textbf{BOOTSTRAP} \ | \ \textbf{JAVASCRIPT} \ | \ \textbf{POSTGRES} \ | \ \textbf{HEROKU} \ | \ \textbf{GITHUB}$

• Used built-in AbstractBaseUser as parent Auth Model. Build Custom Manager for the same. Login. sign up, Logout, and have Account Views Implemented. Deployed on Heroku.

Great Chat, Django Chat Project with Tortoise ORM (SQlite ver) ☑

03/2021 - 03/2021

Checkout **Github** 🛽 or **Live** 🗗

Technologies Used: PYTHON | DJANGO | HTML5 | CSS3 | BOOTSTRAP | JAVASCRIPT | REDIS | SQLITE | POSTGRES | DOCKER | HEROKU | GITHUB

Complete Auth Using Django Default Auth Model. Implemented Chat App using Django
 Channels/Redis/Tortoise ORM with SQLite database. Used Django Groups to create rooms. Deployed on Heroku and Containerized using Docker.

Chew and Cheer, Django Project CRUD using AJAX, DJANGO

02/2021 - 02/2021

FORMS, GRAPHQL and DJANGO REST/GRAPHQL APIs 🛮

Checkout **Github** 🗗 or **Live** 🗗

Technologies Used: PYTHON | DJANGO | JQUERY | GRAPHQL | DJANGO REST FRAMEWORK | HTML | CSS | BOOTSTRAP | JAVASCRIPT | POSTGRES | HEROKU | GITHUB

• Implemented Complete Auth Using Django Default Auth Model. Implemented Crud Operations with Django Forms/Ajax/GraphQl for a restaurant menu. Build Rest API/ GraphQl API. Deployed on Heroku.

Numerical, Django Simple Numeric Calculator ☑

01/2021 - 01/2021

Checkout **Github** ☑ or **Live** ☑

$\textbf{Technologies Used: PYTHON} \ | \ \textbf{DJANGO} \ | \ \textbf{HTML5} \ | \ \textbf{CSS3} \ | \ \textbf{BOOTSTRAP} \ | \ \textbf{JAVASCRIPT} \ | \ \textbf{JQUERY} \ | \ \textbf{HEROKU} \ | \ \textbf{GITHUB}$

• Used SoftUI, Bootstrap, and Jquery to make Pages Dynamic. Calculator Operations +, -, *, / are supported, as well as brackets are evaluated. Deployed on Heroku

Premium Collection Point, *Lic Bill Pay App* ☑

06/2020 - 08/2020

Checkout on **Github** or **Live**

Technologies Used: PYTHON | DJANGO | SELENIUM | HTML | CSS | BOOTSTRAP | JAVASCRIPT | POSTGRES | HEROKU | GITHUB

• Build Web app using Django and Jinja2 Templating along with Bootstrap. Selenium was used to build an API to fetch L.I.C Premium bills. Encryption was used to Implement PCP Pay, as a gateway for loading money into the wallet.

Third Eye, *Diease Predictor App* ☑

01/2019 - 01/2019

Checkout on **Github** ☑ or **Live** ☑

Technologies Used: PYTHON | DJANGO | SCIKIT LEARN | MIND MAX DB | GOOGLE MAPS | HTML5 | CSS3 | BOOTSTRAP | JAVASCRIPT JQUERY | POSTGRES | SQLITE | HEROKU | GITHUB

 Built A simple Web App using Django. Used Naive Bayes Machine Learning algorithm for the training prediction model. Collected data from MIT Website is used for model training. The trained model achieved 97% accuracy. Deployed on Heroku.